Right now,
you're probably hearing
a lot about
Dominion Energy's
$67 billion takeover
by NextEra Energy.
But while the
merger debate dominates
the headlines,
customers of Virginia's
second-largest utility monopoly
are facing yet
another increase
in their
energy bills.
That's right.
If Appalachian Power
Company is your
electric provider,
your bills could
be going
up again.
Is justifying its
request by pointing
to factors
including inflation, storm
recovery expenses
and higher capital
costs. But
what nobody is
talking about
is the elephant
in the room:
their profit, which
is fixed and
guaranteed by
the state.
It's referred to
as return
on equity,
or ROE. And
in Virginia,
overinflated ROE is
one of
the biggest
cost drivers
of rising
energy bills.
It's an issue
that lawmakers representing
Southwest Virginia
tried to fix
during the
legislative session
last year,
but challenging
utilities' profit
means going up
against some
of the
most powerful
corporate lobbying capacity
in the state.
So ultimately, the
bill died.
Now, APCo is
currently authorized to
earn a
9.75% ROE,
which is already
incredibly high,
but it's asking
to increase that
to 10.5%.
The good news
is, if
you're an
APCo customer,
it's not too
late to weigh
in on what
happens next,
and you can
do it from
the comfort
of your
own home.
The SCC will
hear public testimony
by phone
at 10 a.m.
on October 19th.
To sign up,
visit scc.virginia.gov.
Under the Cases
tab, click on
Participating in
SCC Cases,
then scroll down
until you
see Testifying
by Telephone.
Click on the
Public Witness
Appearance Form
and include the
SCC case number,
PUR-2026-00044, along with
your contact information.
That's it.
The SCC will
call you on
the morning of
October 19th
to hear
your testimony.
The deadline to
register is
October 15th,
so mark your
calendars, sign up
and make your
voice heard.